Bernard Muller

Software Engineer

Contact

Address

Cape Town, WC, 7708

Phone

+27 78 213 3024

E-mail

me@bernardmuller.dev

Online Profiles

Github: https://github.com/bernardmuller

Linkedin:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/bernard-muller-

a9a53a174

Personal:

https://bernardmuller.dev

Skills

React

Node

TypeScript

JavaScript

PostgresSQL

MongoDB

Git

REST

Proactive professional with 3+ years of experience in a work environment and a proven knowledge of problem solving through design. Actively expanding my skillset and aiming to leverage my skills to successfully fill a Fullstack Software Engineer role.

Work History

2021-09 -Current

Software Engineer

Hatronika (Pty) Ltd, Cape Town, WC

- Led the development and implementation of a large-scale, comprehensive event/staff management website that works in tandem with a Web3 NFT mobile app.
- Contributed in discussions with the UX/UI designers and project architect to deliver the expected product both from a business logic and UI design perspective.

2019-02 -2021-09

Architectural Technologist

CNR Architects CC, Cape Town, WC

My primary role at CNR Architects was not at all tech or programming related, although I did consult with the team to develop a small in house desktop app/ web app to manage their timesheets.

I also acquired valuable transferable skills that helped me transition into the tech industry.

Transferrable skills I learned:

- How to approach technical problems by splitting the problem up into smaller pieces, while keeping the end goal in mind.
- Communicate effectively with colleagues/other consultants and work efficiently within a team.
- Time management.
- How to cope under pressure.

As an architectural technologist, I helped with the design and document luxury hotels currently being built in countries like Vietnam, AUE and Seychelles. My responsibilities were to collaborate with various

Python

consultants to ensure the BIM models stay compatible with one another and generate technical details based on the building's design.

Education

2020-11 - 2021-03	The Web Developer Bootcamp 2020: Software Development Udemy
2015-01 - 2018-12	Bachelor's Degree: Architecture University of Pretoria
2021-10 - 2021-12	Microservices With NodeJs And React Udemy
2021-01 - 2021-05	React - The Complete Guide (incl Hooks, React Rout Udemy
2010-01 - 2014-12	National Senior Certificate Hoërskool Montana - Montana, Pretoria

Projects

Personal website

One of my first projects I built when starting to learn Reactjs. Wanted to create my own little corner on the internet, where I can showcase my growth. On of the projects I frequently come back to and update.

https://www.bernardmuller.dev/

Source: https://github.com/bernardmuller/personalsite

Munchies v1

A full stack web app to automate my household grocery lists based on meals we plan to eat throughout the week. An ongoing side project I use to advance my skills in my off time.

Technologies used: ReactJs, Express, NodeJs, MongoDB, JsonWebTokens, Styled Components, Mongoose.

Backend: https://github.com/bernardmuller

/munchies-BE

Frontend: https://github.com/bernardmuller/menuApp

Munchies v2

A refactor of Munchies v1. After 2months of using Munchies v1, I discovered a lot of bugs and faults in the overall design.

Munchies v1 has exactly the same features and functionality as v1, but the underlying architecture is designed to allow for more scaling, new features in future and is designed to be a Progressive Web App. Technologies used: TypeScript, Nextjs, GraphQL, NodeJs, PostgresSQL, Prisma, MaterialUI/Styled-Components, JsonWebTokens.

https://munchiesapp.co.za

Backend: https://github.com/bernardmuller/munchies

Frontend: https://github.com/bernardmuller

/munchies-pwa

SplitSmart

A Project I'm developing with a friend that allows you to set up transaction splitting with another user on Splitwise. The app has an SMTP and HTTP server listening on a DigitalOcean droplet for incoming emails from your bank, then sends you a link to the frontend where you are able to setup your transaction split.

Technologies used: TypeScript, Node, Express.

Auto Timesheet

My first python project I built for my colleagues to manage their work logging into Excel Spreadsheets. Technologies used: Python, PyQT5, OpenPyExcel Source: https://github.com/bernardmuller/auto_timesheet

TimesheetWeb

Auto timesheet, but built with web technologies. Lets you create multiple "timesheets" to log your work everyday. You can download your timesheets as XLSX files.

Technologies used: Express, Node, MongoDB, Express-

session, Bootstrap.

https://timesheets-cnr.herokuapp.com/

Source: https://github.com/bernardmuller/timesheet